We saw earlier that the rank IC can tell us overall how well
我们之前发现 排名 IC 可以告诉我们
an Alpha vector's predictions align
Alpha 向量的预测
with the subsequent stock returns for the next period.
与下个时期的后续股票收益率之间总体匹配度如何
You may be wondering if it's possible to drill down
你可能会疑问 我们能否详细地查看
deeper to look at the Alpha values assigned each stock
分配给每支股票的 Alpha 值
to see which subset of stocks actually
看看哪一部分股票
contribute most or least to the factor return of the portfolio.
对投资组合的因子收益率贡献最多或最少
Ideally, if our Alpha model and hypothesis were accurate,
理想情况下 如果 Alpha 模型和假说正确的话
the stock with the highest Alpha value for that day
当天 Alpha 值最高的股票
would also have the highest positive return the next day.
在第二天也会具有最高的正收益率
Similarly, the stock with the lowest Alpha value for
同理 当天 Alpha 值最低的股票
that day would also have the lowest return in the next day,
第二天也具有最低的收益率
which would be good for our theoretical portfolio since we would be shorting that stock.
这对我们的理论投资组合来说是好事 因为我们会做空该股票
Remember, that we are working with
注意 我们处理的是
perhaps hundreds or even thousands of stocks in our universe.
股票池中的数百个甚至数千个股票
So, a good middle ground is to divide our Alpha vector into
好的折中点是将 Alpha 向量划分成分位数
quantiles and analyze their returns and volatility within those quantiles.
然后根据这些分位数衡量收益率和波动性
An ideal Alpha model would be one where the group of stocks containing
在理想的 Alpha 模型中
the highest Alpha values for that day would also have the highest average return,
当天包含最高 Alpha 值的股票组将具有最高的平均收益率
and possibly, the highest risk adjusted to return.
并且可能具有最高的风险调整后收益率
Similarly, the group of stocks containing
同理 包含最低 Alpha 值的股票组
the lowest Alpha values would ideally have the lowest returns.
理想情况下具有最低的收益率
For example, if we have 25 stocks in our universe
例如 假设股票池中有 25 支股票
and wanted divide them up each into five groups of equal size,
我们希望按照相同的规模将它们分成五组
we would be using five quantiles also called quintiles.
所以我们将使用五个分位数 也称为五分位
For each day, we'll sort the stocks by their Alpha value.
对于每一天 我们按照 Alpha 值对股票排序
The five highest values go in the fifth group,
五个最高的值进入第五个小组
which are above the fourth quintile.
它们高于第四五分位
The stocks with the lowest five values go in the first group,
五个最低的值进入第一组
which are below the first quintile.
它们低于第一五分位
Similarly, we fill groups 2, 3,
我们同样地根据 Alpha 值
4, with five stocks each based on their Alpha value.
为第二组 第三组和第四组分配五支股票
We can keep track of the individual returns within
我们可以跟踪每组中的每支股票
each of the five groups over a time window such as one,
在某个时间窗口内的收益率
three, or five years.
例如一年 三年或五年
Then we can calculate the mean return within
然后计算每组的平均收益率
each group as well as the standard deviation.
以及标准差
We can call what we just did quantile analysis or quantile performance.
这种分析称为分位数分析或分位数业绩
Since we chose five quantiles,
我们选择了五个分为数
we can also call this quintile performance.
也称为五分位业绩